delorme.com 2004-12-06

# DeLorme | Privacy Statement

DeLorme Privacy Statement

DeLorme's goal is to completely satisfy our customers with products and services of the highest value. The information you provide us can help us meet your needs and exceed your expectations. At the same time, we have a deep respect for personal privacy and wish to use such information only for your benefit. To that end we have updated our privacy policy effective August 2, 2004.

This statement explains our practices concerning the collection and use of customer information. Practices may change over time as we consider new technologies and customer needs. Any changes to our privacy policy will be posted here and we encourage you to review this site periodically. 

This Privacy Statement explains the following:

  * What information we collect 
  * How we use the information we collect 
  * How we use email
  * Children's Privacy
  * How you can update your preferences
  * How to contact us

What information we collect

We may the collect the following information:

  * Name
  * Business name
  * Address
  * Telephone number
  * Email address
  * Credit card information
  * Voluntary customer survey responses

We require only the information needed to process your order or register your product. Items for these purposes are indicated by red asterisks on the entry forms. Some forms, or voluntary customer surveys, might also request optional information such as your hobbies, or other individual preferences. Unless you place an order, register a product or use a service provided by DeLorme, we do not collect or know your name or email address. DeLorme does not follow your browsing activity outside of our site.

How we use the information we collect

We use the information we collect to:

  * Process your order
  * Contact you regarding service requests
  * Alert you to the status of your order
  * Inform you of specific inventory replenishments, if requested
  * Send promotional offers of interest to you
  * Email our newsletter(s) to you, if requested
  * Aid in the development of new or improved products or services

If you provide your email, postal address or phone number, we may use them to communicate with you, but we will not do so if you don't want us to.

DeLorme greatly values you as a customer and respects your desire for privacy regarding your personal information. We are not in the practice of routinely selling or renting names, addresses, or other identifying information to outside parties. Yet, there are occasional opportunities or needs to make our mailing list or general shopping activity available to carefully selected marketing service providers whose privacy practices meet the Direct Marketing Association’s privacy standards. These service providers could include credit card processors, email distributors, shipping services, market research and promotions managers or list analysts and providers. In any case, our partners are not permitted to provide this information to another party. DeLorme considers such relationships only if we truly believe in their benefit to our customers and our products; however if you do not wish to be included, please let us know.  
  
In order to continually improve our Web site, we do study how people navigate through it, and which areas are popular and more meaningful. We may collect aggregate information site-wide, including site usage statistics and transaction information. We log domain names and/or IP addresses. Please keep in mind that such information is analyzed only in aggregate and is not personally identifiable.

How we use email

DeLorme will email your online order and shipment confirmations to you. We occasionally send email notices of upgrades, special offers and new product announcements. We may also solicit your input on new products or feedback on existing ones. You may remove your name from our email list at any time by following the "Unsubscribe" instructions at the bottom of any email message from us. You will continue to receive email order confirmations.

Children's Privacy

DeLorme does not knowingly collect or use information from persons under 13 years of age. All registrations, purchases, and requests for information by anyone under 13 must be submitted by the parent or guardian. DeLorme will not share information with selected partners (as described above) regarding customers of any of its products that are likely to be used by young children unless the registrant submits such a preference.

How you can update your preferences

You may update your preferences at any time by filling out our Preferences form.

How to contact us

If your question or concern is specifically about privacy, send email to [privacy@delorme.com](mailto:privacy@delorme.com). 

We welcome your comments and are always glad to answer your questions. See Contact Us.
